what's up everybody phil bleckman with
barban.com and today we're going to talk
about some at-home workouts that you can
do for both strength and power if you
want to learn anything about home
workouts that you can do just head over
to google type in home workouts barban
and we have a slew of content that will
help you find what's right for you
regardless of your goals or experience
level you don't need fancy gym equipment
to get in a solid workout sure it can be
nice to have fun toys to play with but
all you need to gain strength build
muscle get your heart rate up or dig
your toes into exercise is your own body
so today we're gonna run through the
benefits of working out at home along
with how to get ready to warm up to take
on our top five at home workouts for
strength muscle growth power and more
let's talk about the benefits of
training at home with your own body
weight first and foremost is convenience
working out at home is convenient you
don't need to commute to the gym or
remember to pack your gear in your
workout bag the second benefit is you
improve mental discipline although it
might seem oxymoronic it takes many
lifters more mental discipline to train
at home than it does to train at the gym
there's a ritual of going to the gym and
many athletes find it comforting but
when you're at home it's easier to be
overcome by momentum and the lack of
separation between relaxation and
training time mixing the two can be
difficult and so improving mental
discipline is a big benefit of training
at home and third potential for improved
coordination when you're training with
only what you have around you at home
you're bound to become more aware of
your body the chair you're using for
dips is stable yes but it's also
slightly tilted to one side if you're at
home improved coordination is a benefit
of potentially body weight workouts
let's dive into how to warm up for home
workouts you'll help make your body more
resilient against injury by warming up
and you'll give yourself a more
effective workout for example when
you're looking to go all out with
push-ups activating your shoulders
waking up your lats and pre-engaging
your chest will lubricate the movement
to make you more efficient and when
you're more efficient you become
stronger and a better overall athlete
let's dive into one of the best home
workouts for strength if you want to get
stronger it's normal for your instinct
to reach for the heaviest weights
possible that said it's completely
possible to develop strength outside of
the barbell-laden gym this homework out
for strength will help you reduce weak
spots in your movement and make you a
lot stronger at the same time depending
on your training experience you can
perform this workout up to three or even
four times a week just making sure
you're sleeping enough and making your
recovery a priority rest for two minutes
between sets to maximize each effort in
this case it's better to rest a little
longer so you can eke out more efficient
reps than to rest shorter and ultimately
complete fewer reps volume is better in
this instance moving on to the best home
workout for muscle growth or hypertrophy
when it comes to packing on mass onto
your frame progressive overload is the
most important factor weights are
beneficial because it is easier to
simply pick up a heavier dumbbell than
what you used to the week before however
you can add additional stress to your
muscles by adjusting your lifting tempo
shortening your rest time between sets
and increasing the number of reps you do
each week or each workout so perform
this workout two to three times a week
you might be able to increase that
number to four if you're accustomed to
higher training frequency and your
recovery is on point rest for at least
90 seconds between sets and use that
time to take long slow breaths recapture
your breathing stabilize yourself before
you dive back in this will help you
remember the importance of breathing
during tempo training let's shift over
to the best homework out for power even
if you're landing softly power workouts
don't tend to be the quietest if you
live above neighbors you can modify
these exercises to not make such a bang
on their ceiling with the jump squat for
example sink into the deepest part of
the squat as slowly as possible and then
explode up with a lot of force but only
allow your heels to actually leave the
ground this will allow you to get the
same benefits from performing a full
jump squat without actually having to do
the jump and therefore the landing and
disturbing your neighbors keep your
knees on the ground with the ply of
push-ups so you can land softer with
your hands of course you can also take
this workout outside where they're
permitting and still we'll call it a
home workout let's say you're looking
for a home workout to get that heart
rate up we got the best homework out for
cardio no traditional cardio equipment
at home no problem home workouts can be
an excellent way of getting in your
cardio training even without having to
dig out your running shoes you won't
need any equipment but this is still a
high intensity workout so make sure
you're listening to your body and
drinking plenty of water to stay
hydrated you can perform this workout
between two to four times a week
depending on your experience level and
the quality of your recovery rest is
needed between sets but try to keep
track of your rest time your goal over
the weeks will be to gradually and
naturally reduce the amount of time you
feel you need to continue with quality
reps and now if you're a beginner and
you've made it this far into the video
and you're like wait i need a workout
for me at home we got you covered you
don't need lifting experience to become
a successful athlete you just need the
willingness to take things slow pay
strict attention to your form and listen
to your body if you can't do a full
push-up there's absolutely no shame in
that simply take your time and build up
to it everyone's body is different and
your job while working out at home is to
learn more about your own body's needs
the keys to any workout are proper form
and listening to your body if once a
week is what feels best for you then
perform this once a week if you'd like
to commit to two or even three times per
week then go for it just listen to your
body remember recovery needs to be on
point so whether you're working out
while traveling for the holidays or just
trying to keep your program as simple
and commute free as possible there are
home workouts for you that are
infinitely adjustable and customizable
to your schedule assess your goals and
starting point and then get after it
even if you're used to hauling heavy
weights you have nothing to lose and
everything to gain by training at home
if there are any other home workouts
that you would like to take a look at
just head over to google type in home
workouts bar bend all of our homework
our coverage is going to come up and you
will not want to miss out we have a lot
of content that you can sift through and
find what is best for your needs i'm
phil bleckman for barbin.com thanks for
watching
[Music]